[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5d5", "question": "What is the capital of Kosovo?", "answer": "Pristina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bba", "question": "For how many years were Madonna and Sean Penn married?", "answer": "4", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf6", "question": "What sporting event is also called \"birling\"?", "answer": "Log rolling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b8e", "question": "What form of writing is literally translated to \"sacred writings\"?", "answer": "Hieroglyphics", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd3", "question": "What Chinese-born architects designed the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame?", "answer": "I. M. Pei", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c1e4877e98cb97778980", "question": "Where can you find the world's oldest lake?", "answer": "Siberia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c308", "question": "How long is the giraffe's tongue?", "answer": "17 inches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c852", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the pyloris?", "answer": "The stomach", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7cfbe877e98cb97778a53", "question": "Miami, Florida sits on the bank of what bay?", "answer": "Biscayne Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57d", "question": "Kodiak Island is the largest island in which US state?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e7fdfe83fe1f2a824bd8", "question": "Who was the wife of the future Henry VIII\u2019s older brother, Arthur?", "answer": "Catherine of Aragon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f91", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"The Turning Point\"?", "answer": "Leslie Brown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a424", "question": "In what state would you find the supposed UFO site named \"Area 51\"?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59decfdeea2747c8aff16d21", "question": "In the 15th Century, in which ship did John Cabot sail to Canada?", "answer": "Matthew of Bristol", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b03f", "question": "What was the first country to formally recognize the independence of the United States?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf7", "question": "What is actress Julia Roberts' middle name?", "answer": "Fiona", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392bf", "question": "What was the British equivalent to the popular American MTV show \"Jersey Shore\"?", "answer": "Geordie Shore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd530e347d002c297e4b5", "question": "Which book did James Fenimore Cooper publish in 1826 that was later made into a movie, starring Daniel Day-Lewis?", "answer": "The Last of the Mohicans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d2", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"Mad Anthony\"?", "answer": "Anthony Wayne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec7", "question": "Who was fired from the Interior Department in 1865 for having written \"Leaves of Grass\"?", "answer": "Walt Whitman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe738e8eec85e375820b26a", "question": "Where is the USA's first ski town located?", "answer": "Woodstock, Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8a7", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named for a Scottish village?", "answer": "Strontium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6008de03f4f3bc4a292f8627", "question": "Who wrote \"Letter from Birmingham Jail\"?", "answer": "Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. -- The civil rights leader wrote the letter as an open letter on April 16, 1963.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a10b20565ad31a57c79f", "question": "Which country created the official marathon length of 26.2 miles?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a261", "question": "Which British group recorded the song \"The House of the Rising Sun\" in 1964?", "answer": "The Animals", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339149", "question": "Who wrote the \"Shogun\" series of novels?", "answer": "James Clavell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c44e", "question": "What are scientists hoping to cause when they seed a cloud?", "answer": "Rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600242dc4be4723ccac2218e", "question": "Which war novel follows the life of Captain John Yossarian?", "answer": "\"Catch-22\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa77173838c5c8a417f38", "question": "What are people who love eating ice called?", "answer": "Pagophagiacs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe734f2eec85e375820b240", "question": "What prison held Rudolf Hess after World War II?", "answer": "Spandau Prison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdcd", "question": "What kind of tea takes its name from the Chinese for \"Black dragon\"?", "answer": "Oolong", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b217", "question": "Who was assassinated by Talmadge Hayer?", "answer": "Malcolm X", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd5", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"canyon\"?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4ddb406d333868d34d707", "question": "Who was known as the \"Mad Monarch\"?", "answer": "George III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f6fcda9e54d890926f6d3", "question": "The southernmost city in the world is located in which country?", "answer": "Chile -- Ushuaia, Argentina held the title until 2019, when Chilean authorities upgraded the town Puerto Williams to city status.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a569", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Keystone State\"?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e1d", "question": "What Grimm's fairy-tale character is named for a vegetable craved by her pregnant mother?", "answer": "Rapunzel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58dba25c874c93a3298b2132", "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Zeus place in the heavens as the constellation Ursa Major?", "answer": "Callisto", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600cc8606de0eb824d4052fb", "question": "Where is the world's largest Roman aqueduct that is still in use?", "answer": "Spain -- The Segovia aqueduct, built in the first century A.D., carries water from the Fuente Fr\u00eda River to the city of Segovia.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba99", "question": "Where did former NFL star Joe Montana play college football?", "answer": "Notre Dame", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d7", "question": "Which actor played the role of God in the movie \"Bruce Almighty\"?", "answer": "Morgan Freeman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e5", "question": "The Khyber pass joins which\u00a0two countries?", "answer": "Afghanistan and Pakistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d7", "question": "Meg Ryan and Tom Hanks appeared together for the first time in which movie?", "answer": "Joe Versus the Volcano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae4d", "question": "In 1819, the US purchased Florida from what country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fecdd29ec223966ae8f8900", "question": "What band is the film \"Bohemian Rhapsody\" about?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd2c", "question": "In what sport are the Beaters in charge of batting away the Bludgers?", "answer": "Quidditch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133949e", "question": "Who wrote the novel the miniseries \"Shogun\" was based on?", "answer": "James Clavell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca00", "question": "What is the technical term for an organism that eats other organisms as food?", "answer": "A heterotroph", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d35", "question": "Who's responsible for performing \"The Ballad of The Green Berets\"?", "answer": "Barry Sadler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e0d2fe83fe1f2a824b92", "question": "Against which country did the Soviet Union instigate an armed conflict in late 1939?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c21a", "question": "Which country were the 1952 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff6690552a821ff76ae8b08", "question": "Who renamed the U.S. presidential yacht \"Honey Fritz,\" in honor of his grandfather, a former Boston mayor?", "answer": "President John F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab7a", "question": "What year did Mauritius gain its independence from Britain?", "answer": "1968", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aecd", "question": "What US general accepted the surrender of Japan?", "answer": "General Douglas MacArthur", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaaf", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Argentina?", "answer": "Rufous Hornero", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc5", "question": "Ditra Flame was the \"Lady in Black\" who took thirteen red roses to what actor's grave every year?", "answer": "Rudolph Valentino's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f9a", "question": "What character from a pop song wears a screwed-down hairdo and snow-white tan?", "answer": "Ziggy Stardust", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590680e1ff9c0647b50a8090", "question": "What company was founded in October, 2016, to relaunch an all-electric vehicle that had previously failed?", "answer": "Fisker Inc.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6aa5f20565ad31a57c817", "question": "Who was the mayor of Chicago from 1955 to 1976?", "answer": "Richard J. Daley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339464", "question": "In what US town does the movie \"Groundhog Day\" take place?", "answer": "Punxutawney, PA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b073", "question": "Who was the first Secretary of the Treasury of the United States?", "answer": "Alexander Hamilton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8cc", "question": "What city is home to the eighty-eight storey Petronas Twin Towers?", "answer": "Kuala Lumpur", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd9e", "question": "Who would typically use a Punnett square?", "answer": "A biologist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a766", "question": "In which US state is Oral Roberts University located?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339804", "question": "What movie soundtrack is Eric Clapton's \"Tears in Heaven\" from?", "answer": "Rush", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae98", "question": "Who was US president when the stock market crashed in 1929?", "answer": "Herbert Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015ffcafe83fe1f2a824c50", "question": "In the film \"Saving Private Ryan,\" who played the role of private Ryan?", "answer": "Ironically Matt Damon was given this role by Spielberg partly due to his lack of fame.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c753", "question": "What scale is used to measure the hardness of minerals?", "answer": "The Mohs Scale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338920", "question": "What spice is the most essential and valuable commodity in the \"Dune\" universe?", "answer": "Melange", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e6b70ffb6c85e9e634ff4a", "question": "Who composed and played the score for the film 1953 film \"Genevieve\"?", "answer": "Larry Adler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594a64c22ebb971c1417fba7", "question": "Who was the first US actress to be featured on a US postage stamp?", "answer": "Grace Kelly", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388eb", "question": "What is the dot in the \"i\" called?", "answer": "A tittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339822", "question": "What American opera singer was nicknamed \"Bubbles\"?", "answer": "Beverly Sills", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c385", "question": "In medical terminology, the \"voice box\" is known as what?", "answer": "Larynx", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76838eec85e375820b29d", "question": "What group of countries are often referred to as Great Britain?", "answer": "England, Scotland, and Wales", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338db6", "question": "In what ominous numbered room is Winston Smith strapped to a chair at the end of \"Nineteen Eighty-Four\"?", "answer": "Room 101", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cd9a4e347d002c297e4cd", "question": "In modern badminton, how many points typically win a singles game?", "answer": "21", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c17a", "question": "What object is said to bring bad luck if it is broken?", "answer": "Mirror", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f1b", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both John Gavin and Rex Harrison?", "answer": "Julius Caesar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133998e", "question": "What was the first spin\u00ad-off series of the TV show \"The Cosby Show\"?", "answer": "A Different World", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5eb736465e259d786908732b", "question": "What was the name of the US Navy boat that had the nickname \"Old Ironsides\"?", "answer": "USS Constitution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59049938cf93664eb104868e", "question": "What Charles Dickens work features the character of Mr. Wardle?", "answer": "The Pickwick Papers", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339128", "question": "Who composed the 1877 opera \"Samson and Delilah\"?", "answer": "Camille Saint-Saens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd07", "question": "What hockey great wore the number 68 to commemorate the Prague Spring of 1968?", "answer": "Jaromir Jagr", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c96e", "question": "Ariel is a moon of which planet in the solar system?", "answer": "Uranus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cefc089948005ec986edcdc", "question": "Who is the third member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Haseul", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b5", "question": "What duo starred in the 1989 movie \"When Harry Met Sally\"?", "answer": "Billy Crystal and Meg Ryan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0db34fcbed638185eaa08", "question": "Where is the only tropical botanical garden listed on UNESCO's World Heritage Site list?", "answer": "Singapore", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eae7df83302ff91e46489", "question": "What is a group of deer called?", "answer": "A Herd", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4af249076251badbeabe", "question": "Ruby Bridges became the first Black student to do what?", "answer": "At six-years-old, Ruby Bridges was the first Black child to be integrated into an all-white school in New Orleans in 1960.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a82", "question": "What female dog is the secret object of Underdog\u2019s affection?", "answer": "Sweet Polly Purebred", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf05", "question": "What large red flower is the floral emblem of New South Wales?", "answer": "Waratah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f2", "question": "A light aircraft without an engine is called a what?", "answer": "Glider or a sailplane", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d0d", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"The Quickening\"?", "answer": "Highlander", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea0", "question": "Which Edward was the first ever Prince of Wales?", "answer": "Edward II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a13a", "question": "In the TV series \"The Fall Guy\", who did Lee Majors play?", "answer": "Colt Seavers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e2c", "question": "What musical was based on Thornton Wilder's play \"The Matchmaker\"?", "answer": "Hello, Dolly!", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc0", "question": "In Greek Mythology, what hung from an oak tree in the grove of Ares in Colchis, guarded by a dragon?", "answer": "The Golden Fleece", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f9f48b3af848b908361b879", "question": "How many people made up the US Electoral College in 2020?", "answer": "538", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad67", "question": "The original Teamsters union was formed to protect who?", "answer": "Horse carriage drivers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c031", "question": "What is the fear of fire known as?", "answer": "Pyrophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb61c15dad637d903c8830", "question": "Bammy is a traditional Jamaican bread made primarily of what?", "answer": "Cassava flour", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee3", "question": "By what professional name is comic book writer Stanley Martin Leiber better known?", "answer": "Stan Lee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd5", "question": "Run D.M.C. were the first rap band to appear on the cover of what magazine?", "answer": "Rolling Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339981", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who does Homer consider to be his best friend?", "answer": "Barney Gumble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008f8bcf842fa4c4ba96bd", "question": "Who is the Roman Patron Saint of hangovers?", "answer": "Saint Bibiana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab954286faa38a764be514", "question": "What year did BMW debut the M5?", "answer": "1985", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b906", "question": "What was the first NBA team named after a car part?", "answer": "The Detroit Pistons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339526", "question": "What is the name of the prince in Disney's \"Sleeping Beauty\"?", "answer": "Phillip", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b373541c3f17ccc40c8e2c", "question": "Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\" depicts the courtship of which characters?", "answer": "Petruchio and Katherina", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5a9e95527ccba3ffe45786de", "question": "Malagasy is the native language of which country?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5be581a05415ba52ed6f0ac3", "question": "Who released an autobiography titled \"Making Waves: The Autobiography\"?", "answer": "David Hasselhoff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5cefc125948005ec986edce4", "question": "Who is the eleventh member of the group LOONA to debut", "answer": "Go Won", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b358ba05db0d66a186cb558", "question": "In architecture, what is a \"Purlin\"?", "answer": "A horizontal structural member", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59067c00ff9c0647b50a8069", "question": "What artist received the most Grammy Awards in 2016?", "answer": "Kendrick Lamar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc23eec223966ae8f8873", "question": "Razzie awards are meant to go to bad movies, but who got nominated for directing the now widely respected film Scarface?", "answer": "Brian De Palma", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a899bb860d398dc9cf7a6a0", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the Pelican State?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133914d", "question": "Who was the Greek god of blacksmiths?", "answer": "Hephaestus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febb6f07e83c707845b212c", "question": "What\u2019s the difference between green and black olives?", "answer": "Ripeness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c7", "question": "What baseball team did Cheers' manager Sam Malone play for in the TV show?", "answer": "The Boston Red Sox", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99b6921a8909e5c332d2b", "question": "What year saw the release of the film \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit\"?", "answer": "1988", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59774321284458f1d7854425", "question": "Albert Einstein was offered the position of prime minister of what country?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4b40d06d333868d34d6df", "question": "What part of the world did the Vikings come from?", "answer": "Scandinavia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6aa", "question": "What cave, found in central Kentucky, is the world's longest cave system?", "answer": "Mammoth Cave", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefa9126ce05a3942286edb", "question": "What classic novel did TV's \"Big Brother\" get its name from?", "answer": "1984", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ad", "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Argentina?", "answer": "Aconcagua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339113", "question": "Which publication serialized the 1897 novel \"The Invisible Man\"?", "answer": "Pearson's Weekly", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c88e6b222f44c2d77a29c42", "question": "Who wrote both \"Anna Karenina\" and \"War and Peace\"?", "answer": "Leo Tolstoy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c15f", "question": "Fax is short for which word?", "answer": "Facsimile", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb54b65ff7d326b622a90", "question": "In Shakespeare's play \"Titus Andronicus\", who is Titus' daughter?", "answer": "Lavinia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae2e", "question": "Who is widely credited for sewing the first American flag?", "answer": "Betsy Ross", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba48", "question": "What US city hosts the world's largest hot air balloon festival?", "answer": "Albuquerque", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b274", "question": "What army occupied Addis Ababa in May 1936?", "answer": "Italy's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a011", "question": "Who lost forty-three pounds for his one-scene role in \"The Sixth Sense\"?", "answer": "Donnie Wahlberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee4", "question": "Which cabinet post did Winston Churchill hold between 1924 and 1929?", "answer": "Chancellor of the Exchequer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beaa", "question": "What cousin of the glockenspiel was named for its ethereal, \"heavenly\" sound?", "answer": "The celesta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c76", "question": "What philosopher/author lived on the shores of Walden Pond?", "answer": "Henry David Thoreau", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb3", "question": "Which Egyptian city was founded by Alexander the Great in 331 BC?", "answer": "Alexandria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7e737b24f84e0b9f9ffb7", "question": "Whose voice, made popular by the Star Wars franchies, narrated the 1995 film \"Judge Dredd\"?", "answer": "James Earl Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f33d01dd7bf43be5e816", "question": "In the US, what does AARP stand for?", "answer": "American Association of Retired Persons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a33", "question": "Who played the Reverend Jim Ignatowski on the TV show \"Taxi\"?", "answer": "Christopher Lloyd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c67c", "question": "Bruxism is a medical term for when a person does what?", "answer": "Grinds their teeth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b3e5e662d71a53650fe6", "question": "What was one of Franz Liszt's most notable talents?", "answer": "Ability to improvise", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b316", "question": "On April 11, 1990, California Angel Mike Witt combined with which starter to pitch a no-hit victory?", "answer": "Mark Langston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10b", "question": "Who was elected to the Senate seat vacated by New York Democrat Daniel Patrick Moynihan on January 3, 2001?", "answer": "Hillary Rodham Clinton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de7", "question": "What 1971 film was partially set in the Korova Milk Bar?", "answer": "A Clockwork Orange", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c68", "question": "What was the name of John Travolta's character in the 1977 movie \"Saturday Night Fever\"?", "answer": "Tony Manero", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cdbb877e98cb97778a3a", "question": "In which European city would you find Orly airport?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feddd666ce05a3942286da3", "question": "In the film \"The Shawshank Redemption,\" Captain Hadley's brother left him inheritance money. What industry was his brother in?", "answer": "Railroad", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a36f", "question": "What body of water does the Danube River flow into?", "answer": "The Black Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b1", "question": "What good little witch is Casper's friend?", "answer": "Wendy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a47", "question": "What comic strip was set in the Okeefenokee Swamp?", "answer": "Pogo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3586ff048f679a45ab03", "question": "A single piece of coiled DNA is known as what?", "answer": "Chromosome", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f7122a9e54d890926f6db", "question": "Which country claims the island of Saipan as a commonwealth?", "answer": "USA -- Saipan is part of the Northern Mariana Islands, which is a commonwealth of the U.S.  Saipan is the seat of the government.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ef", "question": "In the TV show \"Growing Pains\", what was Boner's dad's name?", "answer": "Sylvester Stabone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab145dbaab681b09292173", "question": "What year did Volkswagen introduce the Golf GTI?", "answer": "1976", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba28", "question": "Arthur Ashe is best known for his career in what sport?", "answer": "Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea7", "question": "What flower symbolizes the throne of the Japanese emperor?", "answer": "The chrysanthemum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8acec01dd7bf43be5e772", "question": "When primary colors are mixed together, they create what?", "answer": "Secondary colors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394db", "question": "Who played the role of Kevin Arnold on \"The Wonder Years\"?", "answer": "Fred Savage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e4", "question": "What kind of a car travels through time in the movie \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "DeLorean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339999", "question": "What jazz saxophonist was nicknamed \"Bird\"?", "answer": "Charlie Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25f2f96682715b82711cef", "question": "What is Joseph Priestley credited with discovering?", "answer": "Oxygen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cddb5e347d002c297e4f3", "question": "Which 1960s singer/songwriter was voted \"Ugliest Man on Campus\" while attending college?", "answer": "Janis Joplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a74990aac110e4167085", "question": "What province in China does Pu-erh tea originate from?", "answer": "Yunnan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339995", "question": "What was the name of He-Man's main nemesis on \"He-Man and the Masters of the Universe\"?", "answer": "Skeletor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c748fbde8045e48466c0", "question": "What architectural event occurs at the Mayan Temple of Kukulcan?", "answer": "During the equinoxes, a shadow resembling a snake can be seen running down the Mayan Temple of Kukulcan.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66216a5bfecdd737e0841", "question": "Who was on the first cover of \"Rolling Stone\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e4", "question": "Which popular musician co-wrote the song \"I'm afraid of Americans\" with David Bowie?", "answer": "Brian Eno", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb69685dad637d903c8847", "question": "Who played the wife of Goose in the film \"Top Gun\"?", "answer": "Meg Ryan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b304", "question": "What title was given to Nanak, the founder of Sikhism?", "answer": "Guru", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e54", "question": "What literary work inspired Led Zeppelin's \"The Battle of Evermore\" song?", "answer": "The Lord of the Rings", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5b", "question": "What literary work inspired Dream Theater's \"Pull Me Under\" song?", "answer": "Hamlet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c749", "question": "What is the only rock that will float on water?", "answer": "Pumice", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339684", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who shot Mr. Burns?", "answer": "Maggie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab56", "question": "What is the largest country in South America?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59db78230ab2c8f322317ff2", "question": "Which author wrote about the Cornish seaside boarding school Malory Towers?", "answer": "Enid Blyton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c39", "question": "What book won Harper Lee a Pulitzer Prize in 1961?", "answer": "To Kill A Mockingbird", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf3", "question": "What medical term is used to describe the process of sweating?", "answer": "Hydrosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdab5370b8cce1e6fda704b", "question": "How can you tell if cranberries are ripe?", "answer": "They bounce like rubber balls", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f74701dd7bf43be5e836", "question": "The board game Parcheesi is based off a board game from what country?", "answer": "India", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab0c04baab681b09292167", "question": "What 2005 horror short film shares a name with a piece of jewelry?", "answer": "Rings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000ed939a72b906b34e3cee", "question": "What is the name of the apparatus used to measure an unknown electrical resistance by balancing two legs of a circuit?", "answer": "The Wheatstone Bridge, named after its inventor, Sir Charles Wheatstone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d5a", "question": "Where was Wonder Woman born?", "answer": "Paradise Island", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b26", "question": "In \"Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs\", which dwarf's job is it to check the authenticity of the gems they mine?", "answer": "Doc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c2", "question": "What is a Googol?", "answer": "1 with 100 zeroes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbdce6ce05a3942286ee2", "question": "What is the name of the saloon featured in the radio and television drama \"Gunsmoke\"?", "answer": "Long Branch Saloon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3f28c73aa70ea0b70afd", "question": "Mount Godwin Austen, located in the Karakoram mountain range, is better known as what?", "answer": "K2", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cb2", "question": "Whose adventures on TV take place on the fictional Island of Sodor?", "answer": "Thomas the Tank Engine's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a7", "question": "What country borders only Brazil, Argentina, and the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "Uruguay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ad", "question": "The assassination of what country's Archduke led to World War I?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b066", "question": "In 1967, what company introduced the first consumer model of microwave oven designed for home use?", "answer": "Amana", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e3", "question": "Who is the author of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" novel series?", "answer": "Robert Ludlum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601371ad138175489539638c", "question": "Which musician wrote the theme song for Johnny Carson's \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Paul Anka -- The song earned him huge royalties: at the peak of the show's popularity, he took home $800,000 to $900,000 annually.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eaec8f83302ff91e4648c", "question": "Mark David Chapman became famous for what in 1980?", "answer": "Shooting John Lennon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fb2", "question": "Which German city was the birthplace of the poet Heinrich Heine?", "answer": "Dusseldorf", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a63", "question": "What Shakespeare work includes the line \"Friends, Romans, countrymen, lend me your ears\"?", "answer": "Julius Caesar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59071b743745b36be73039c1", "question": "What year did the Chew comics series debut?", "answer": "2009", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf47", "question": "What is the flower that stands for sensitiveness?", "answer": "Mimosa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf3", "question": "What year saw the release of the game Space Invaders?", "answer": "1978", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f95b1bc55722f97b22684de", "question": "What year did the Original Dungeons and Dragons box set by Gary Gygax and Dave Arneson debut?", "answer": "1974", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a56a", "question": "What is the two letter postal abbreviation for the state of Virginia?", "answer": "VA", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b323514bf195a31e15d73ab", "question": "Sergey Bubka has set a world record in which field event over 30 times?", "answer": "Pole Vault", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ecc", "question": "What rapper performs at the \"Mitch-a-palooza\" in the movie \"Old School\"?", "answer": "Snoop Dogg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b003", "question": "In 1810, New York overtook what city as America's most populated city?", "answer": "Philadelphia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c1b", "question": "The comic books and movie titled \"300\" is based off of which famous battle?", "answer": "The Battle of Thermopylae", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b5", "question": "The March of Dimes was originally founded to help find a vaccine for what?", "answer": "Polio", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c949", "question": "In which continent did Turkeys originate?", "answer": "North America", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c81d", "question": "Starfish belong to what animal phylum, whose name means \"spiny skin\"?", "answer": "Echinoderms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c97e", "question": "What lives in a formicary?", "answer": "Ants", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af68", "question": "Who did George Washington name as vice president?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b160", "question": "What title was Mother Teresa given by Pope John Paul II after her death?", "answer": "Blessed Teresa of Calcutta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d59", "question": "What is Wonder Woman's most notable alias?", "answer": "Diana Prince", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523da6736d4be723796b45", "question": "What was the last Province or Territory that joined Canada?", "answer": "Nunavut", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b6", "question": "The TV mini-series \"Rich Man, Poor Man\" was based on the lives of what family?", "answer": "The Jordache Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c87f", "question": "What kind of bird is an eider?", "answer": "A duck", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aca", "question": "The story of Cinderella was written by which French author?", "answer": "Charles Perrault", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f3e001dd7bf43be5e819", "question": "POTUS stands for what?", "answer": "President Of The United States", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b53f", "question": "What letter is least used in the English language?", "answer": "Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5b3", "question": "How many calories are stored in 1 pound of body fat?", "answer": "3500", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb04", "question": "Which member of the British royal family was married to Sarah Ferguson?", "answer": "Prince Andrew", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c064", "question": "In the video game \"God of War\", which mythological character must Kratos defeat at the end to finish the game?", "answer": "Ares (the God of War)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133906c", "question": "Which famous piece of artwork depicts the \"Battle of Hastings\"?", "answer": "Bayeux Tapestry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b94f", "question": "What sport did hall-of-famer Mickey Mantle play?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e1", "question": "P.J. Clapp is better known by what name?", "answer": "Johnny Knoxville", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad1c", "question": "Where was Ben Franklin born?", "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133972a", "question": "Who played weatherman Phil Connors in the movie \"Groundhog Day\"?", "answer": "Bill Murray", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d2d", "question": "The novel \"A Brave New World\" is set in what year?", "answer": "2540", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7fb", "question": "What was the capital city of West Germany from 1949 to 1990?", "answer": "Bonn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a4", "question": "Who released the albums \"At Folsom Prison\" and \"At San Quentin\"?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdeb", "question": "What Burlingame, California, company was founded in 1984 to provide blood and urine analysis to athletes?", "answer": "BALCO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd2", "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Hippomenes defeat in a footrace?", "answer": "Atalanta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59bb29c1c9bff04efae6d759", "question": "Whose novels include \"The Joy Luck Club\" and \"The Kitchen God's Wife\"?", "answer": "Amy Tan's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf5d", "question": "In which athletics event might you use a Fosbury Flop?", "answer": "High Jump", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c310", "question": "What influential French design house manufactures Poison, a line of women's fragrances?", "answer": "Christian Dior", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a609", "question": "In which European country is the resort town of Spa?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b245", "question": "In 2002, Sony ended production of its recorders using what doomed video standard?", "answer": "Betamax", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f16516af9b80650dbe7f93c", "question": "Which Mormon founded Salt Lake City?", "answer": "Brigham Young", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab1a92baab681b09292195", "question": "What celebrity\u2019s car was fixed and raced in the 2009 documentary \u201cLove the Beast\u201d", "answer": "Eric Bana's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ce", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"Old Blood and Guts\"?", "answer": "George Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c32a", "question": "What part of the eye gives it color?", "answer": "The Iris", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f168e3f7c52aae91cc07cb", "question": "What is the core in most pencils made from?", "answer": "Graphite", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a80e", "question": "The city of Roswell, famous for its 1947 UFO incident, is in which state?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e06", "question": "What comic strip introduced the metal band Billy and the Boingers?", "answer": "Bloom County", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133960b", "question": "Who played Captain Leo Davidson in the 2001 version of the movie \"Planet of the Apes\"?", "answer": "Mark Wahlberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d4", "question": "The fruit of the rose plant shares its name with what part of the body?", "answer": "The hips", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a29620565ad31a57c7ae", "question": "Who was the first US presidential candidate to speak at a political convention?", "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339178", "question": "What picture hangs on Andy Dufresne's cell wall in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "A picture of Albert Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af64", "question": "What year was the company \"Hewlett-Packard\" founded?", "answer": "1939", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab87", "question": "What country is Phnom Penh the capital of?", "answer": "Cambodia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be74", "question": "Who were the winners of the James E. Sullivan Award for amateur athletics in 1986 and 1988?", "answer": "Jackie Joyner-Kersee and Florence Griffith-Joyner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa3eb2c73aa70ea0b70af9", "question": "What was an alternative name for Maryland?", "answer": "Mariana (Lord Baltimore squashed the idea because the name reminded him of Spanish Jesuit and historian Juan de Mariana.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b13", "question": "Who did Lionel Richie duet with on the 1981 #1 smash \"Endless Love\"?", "answer": "Diana Ross", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8c8aec223966ae8f884c", "question": "Which famous Christmas movie is based on the story of a boy outsmarting a couple of adult thieves?", "answer": "\"Home Alone\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc2", "question": "What is the last name of the \"Evil Dead\" series protagonist Ash?", "answer": "Williams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dcd", "question": "What British pop group did Bryan Ferry lead after Brian Eno's 1973 departure?", "answer": "Roxy Music", "category": "entertainment"}]